Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
（黄瀬(きせ)）ハァー
Now!
（黄瀬）思ったとおり
やっぱ 青峰っちは スゲー
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
こりゃ いよいよ
覚悟 決めなきゃ マズイっスね
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（今吉(いまよし)）
なんや？ 腹くくった顔しとるな
What's this?
They look pretty motivated.
なんか
仕掛ける気マンマンって感じやん
They must have something planned.
There it is! Kise versus Aomine!
（小金井(こがねい)）来た！ 黄瀬 対 青峰(あおみね)
How many times have they tried this already?
（土田(つちだ)）今日 何度目だ ほんと…
（青峰(あおみね)）あん？
（さつき）え？
（火神(かがみ)）ん？
Hey, what's wrong?
（青峰）オイオイ どしたぁ？
もう お手上げか？
Have you already given up?
What's going on?
（青峰）どういうことだ？ 別に
選択肢はワンオンワンだけじゃねえ
One-on-one isn't his only option,
but he's not coming at me aggressively enough!
が 攻める気がなさすぎる
Episode 24
Don't Get the Wrong Idea
（土田）スティール！
A steal!
It's a turnover!
（日向(ひゅうが)）攻守交代だ
This doesn't seem right.
（青峰）ったく ひっかかるぜ…
攻める気がないかと思えば
なんだ そりゃあ
They don't seem aggressive enough, and then they pull that.
They have no intention of losing.
負ける気もサラサラねーじゃねぇか
ハッ けど まぁ 関係ねぇな
But it doesn't matter.
No matter what you do, the results won't change!
どっちにしろ 結果は変わんねぇ
（福田(ふくだ)）速(はえ)ぇ！
He's so fast!
That's Aomine for you!
（河原(かわはら)）やっぱ 青峰だ！
（笠松(かさまつ)）ぐっ！
Charging! Black No. 5!
（審判）チャージング！ 黒５番！
なっ ファウル！？
What? A foul?
I can't believe it didn't count.
（木吉(きよし)）まさかのノーカンだな
He's good!
（日向）巧(うま)い！
いや それより すげえ度胸だ！
But more than that, he's really got guts!
Instead of stepping back because of the difference in their builds, he held his ground for a foul.
あの体格差で引くどころか—
ファウルもらいに
ぶつかりに いくなんて！
You've really done it now, Senpai.
（青峰）
やってくれんじゃん 先輩
（笠松）あ？ 人 吹っ飛ばしといて
んだ その態度は １年ボーズ！
What?
You just hit a guy. What's with the attitude, kid?
（早川(はやかわ)）さすが キャプテン！
ナイスガッツ！
That's our captain! Nice...
Shut up!
うるせー！
This is making me nervous.
（森山(もりやま)）
けど ヒヤヒヤもんだ できるのか？
Can we really do this?
It's not a matter of can or can't!
（笠松）できるか
できないかじゃねえ！
We're gonna do it! Believe in our ace!
やるんだよ！
ウチのエースを信じろ！
He's not stopping.
止まらねーな
Aomine's going full throttle.
（伊月(いづき)）青峰 全開
What's going on?
（今吉）どういうことや？ タンカ
切ったわりに 何も ないやんけ？
All that talk, and they're not doing anything.
（黄瀬）あー クソッ…
やっぱ メチャクチャ カッケーなぁ
Damn it...
He's so freaking cool.
That absolute style no one can copy...
人にはマネできない
唯一 絶対のスタイル
I started basketball because I looked up to this guy.
この人に憧れて
オレはバスケを始めたんだ
I could make normal plays after seeing them once,
普通のプレーは
見れば すぐ できるのに—
but no matter how many times I tried,
この人のは
何度やっても できなかった
I could never copy his.
けど 分かってたんだ 本当は
なぜ できないか
The truth is, I knew why I couldn't copy them.
Once you look up to someone, you can't overtake them.
憧れてしまえば 超えられない
Kise may indeed be worse than Aomine right now.
（武内(たけうち)）確かに現時点では
黄瀬は青峰に劣っているかもしれん
But I would still choose Kise.
（武内）
だが それでも わしは黄瀬を取った
ポテンシャルは なんら遜色ない
He doesn't lose in potential.
He's an undeniable prodigy too.
あいつも やはり
まぎれもない天才だ
While I wanted to win, I also didn't want him to lose.
（黄瀬）勝ちたいと願いつつ—
心の底では
負けてほしくないと思うから
That's why...
だから—
I'll just stop looking up to him.
憧れるのは もう やめる
Impossible...
（火神(かがみ)）まさか…
It's probably exactly what you're thinking.
（黒子(くろこ)）たぶん その まさかです
黄瀬君がやろうと
していることは—
Kise is trying...
to copy Aomine's style.
青峰君のスタイルのコピーです
Can he... really do that?
そんな… できるのか！？
そもそも
黄瀬君のコピーというのは—
Kise can only copy what he can do.
できることをやっているだけで
できないことはできません
He cannot copy anything he can't do.
W-What?
Put simply, he's just a fast learner.
（リコ）つまり 簡単に言えば
“のみこみが異常に早い”ってこと
He can't recreate the movements of NBA players or anyone better than himself.
ＮＢＡ選手のコピーとか 自分の
能力以上の動きは再現できない
But if he's trying to do something,
だが 逆に言えば それでも
やろうとしてるってことは—
it means he believes he can do it.
できると信じたってことだ
Oh well...
あらら しゃーない
He just threw it up. There's no way it'll go in!
（笠松）
放っただけだ 入るわけねぇ
What?
A buzzer beater!
（伊月）ブザービーターだ
（今吉）ハハッ… いやぁ ついとる
入ってもーたわ
Man, I'm lucky.
It went in.
Kaijo.....................................................................................Touou
The second quarter is over.
（アナウンス）
第２クオーター終了です
We will now have a 10 minute intermission.
これより
10分のインターバルに入ります
...Kaijo High
Dressing Room
（笠松）９点差か…
最後のが決まったのはイタかったな
A nine point difference...
That last shot hurt.
あぁあ クソォー
オェが 最後 ぃバンとってぅゃあ
Damn it, if only I had gotten the rebound!
Rebounds don't matter once it goes in, you idiot.
入っちまったもんに
リバウンド カンケーねえから バカ
黄瀬 あと どんくらい かかる？
Kise, how much longer will it take?
早くて 第３クオーター後半
At the earliest, the second half of the third quarter.
ヘタしたら 第４クオーターまで
かかるかもしんないっス
If I mess up, it might take until the fourth quarter.
Sorry, but could I go outside for a little bit?
すいません
ちょっと 表 出てきて いいスか？
Sure, but come back soon.
ああ すぐ戻れよ
Basically, we have to play the entire third quarter without Kise.
（小堀(こぼり)）つまり
第３クオーター まるまる—
ほぼ 黄瀬ぬきで しのぐってことか
Can we actually do that against Touou?
（笠松）できるか 桐皇(とうおう)相手に…
No, we'll definitely do it!
いや 絶対やる！
だから 頼むぜ 黄瀬！
It's all up to you, Kise!
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
Copy Aomine?
（原澤）青峰君のコピー？
（さつき）はい
Yes. Not a single move, but his entire style,
ただし 技１つではなく
スタイルごとのコピー
including the improvements he has made.
かつ 昔と今のイメージ修正
（さつき）万一 できたとしても
恐らく もう しばらく かかります
Even if he somehow manages to do it, it should take a while longer.
But...
（桜井(さくらい)）そんな…
Coach!
（若松(わかまつ)）監督！ そんなん知って
こいつ 出しとくことねーっスよ！
Knowing that, there's no reason to put him out there!
We should bench him, and—
一度 ひっこめて…
Hey, don't be stupid.
（青峰）オイ オイ！
寝言 言ってんなよ
Why would you put out a weaker lineup on purpose?
わざわざ戦力ダウンしてやって
どーすんだ
このまま行くに決まってんだろ
It's obvious that we'll just keep going like this.
What did you say, you bastard?
んだと！？ 青峰 テメー！
Copy me?
（青峰）オレのコピー？
できるわけねぇだろ？
There's no way he can do that.
仮に 百万歩譲って
できたとしても—
Even if we give him the benefit of the doubt and say he can do it,
the results won't change.
結果は変わんねーんだよ
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
The only one who can beat me is me.
Hello.
どうも
Kurokocchi?!
Chuo Athletic Center
Ch
（黄瀬）黒子っち！？
Chuo Athletic Center
Ch
What's with the dog?
てか なんスか？ その犬
I kept him in my bag while I was watching,
（黒子）
かばんに入れて観戦してたので—
so I thought I would let him get some fresh air during the break.
休憩の間に 外の空気を
吸わせてあげようと思って…
There's plenty I could say about that.
なんつうか
突っ込みどころ 満載っスね
Anyway, what are you doing here?
で 黒子っちは なんで ここに？
We were training nearby until yesterday,
昨日まで近くで合宿だったので—
so we decided to come watch the Inter-High together.
みんなでインターハイを見に
行こうということになったんです
ちぇー 応援しに
来てくれたんじゃないんスね
So you didn't come to cheer me on.
Nope.
（黒子）はい
（黄瀬）ヒドッ！
So mean!
じゃ ちなみに…
By the way...
青峰っちとオレ… 勝つとしたら
どっちだと思うっスか？
Between Aominecchi and me, who do you think will win?
（黒子）分かりません
I don't know.
What?
As long as you don't give up, anything could happen.
ただ 勝負は 諦めなければ
何が起こるか 分からないし—
２人とも
諦めることはないと思います
And I don't think either of you will give up.
だから どっちが勝っても
おかしくないと思います
So...
I don't think it would be strange if either of you won.
ふーん せいぜい 頑張るっスわ
I guess I'll go do my best then.
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）わん！
Huh? What?
（黄瀬）あれ？ なんスか？
I thought you would say, "I'll definitely win!"
いえ てっきり“絶対勝つっス”
とか言うと思ってました
What are you talking about?
（黄瀬）なんスか！？ それ
Of course that's what I'm trying to do,
そりゃ もちろん
そのつもりなんスけど—
正直 自分でも 分かんないっス
but I honestly don't know either.
In middle school, it was natural for us to win, but...
中学のときは
勝つ試合が当たり前だったけど
I feel better now not knowing if I'll win.
勝てるか どうか 分からない
今のほうが 気持ちイイんス
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（テツヤ２号）クゥ〜ン
（桜井）うわっ 前半より
プレッシャーが… 気合 すごっ！
They're applying more pressure than they did in the first half. The intensity's amazing!
（小金井）おおっ いきなり速攻！
A fast break already!
No you don't!
いかせんで！
Right to left crossover...
（今吉）なっっ！？
これは まさか 青峰の！？
Could this be Aomine's...
Foul, holding! Black No. 4!
ファウル
ホールディング！ 黒４番！
He's still incomplete and nothing compared to the real thing,
（さつき）
まだ不完全で 本物には及ばない
but he's learning much faster than I expected!
けど そんな…
予想より はるかに 早い！
Nice foul, Cap—
ナイスファウル キャプテン…
Wakamatsu,
若松… 青峰が
入って来た日のこと 覚えとるか？
do you remember the day Aomine joined?
What?
I thought he seemed promising, and at the same time,
（今吉）
ワシは頼もしいと思うと同時に—
when I imagined playing against him, it gave me goosebumps.
もし 敵やったときを想像して
鳥肌が立ったわ
This isn't good. I've got goosebumps.
（今吉）あかんわ
立ってもーた 鳥肌
（黄瀬）まだイメージとズレてる…
もっと… もっと速く…
It's not quite like I imagined...
Faster... I need to be faster...
Is this Aomine's again?
（桜井）
これ また 青峰さんの！？
プッシング！ 黒６番！
フリースロー！ ツーショット！
Pushing! Black No. 6!
Shooting foul! Two shots!
すっげぇ 黄瀬！ ていうか
完ペキ 青峰みてーじゃん！
Kise's amazing!
He's just like Aomine!
（リコ）いえ たぶん まだ不完全よ
（小金井）え！？
No, it's not perfect yet.
What?
The fact that he only tries it when people other than Aomine come to guard him proves it.
その証拠に—
速攻とかで青峰君以外が
マークに来たときしか やってない
He must think it's still not perfect.
きっと 本人の中で
まだイメージとズレがあるのよ
In other words, when Kise tries to go one-on-one against Aomine again,
つまり 黄瀬が青峰に再び
ワンオンワンを仕掛けたときが—
コピーが完成したときだ
it will be once he's perfected his copy.
（ホイッスル）
（海常(かいじょう)部員１）ナイスシュート！
Nice shot!
He made them both!
（海常部員２）２本 決めたー！
（海常部員３）いいぞ 黄瀬！
Good job, Kise!
All right!
Kaijo.....................................................................................Touou
（観客）
追上げてきた 海常も粘るぞ！
They're catching up!
Kaijo's fighting back!
That was a shot?
（観客１）
シュートだったのか！？ 今の
He's crazy!
（観客２）
あいつ ムチャクチャだ！
Don't drag your feet, Kise.
（青峰）
タラタラしてんじゃねーよ 黄瀬
If you don't make it in time, it's over.
別に 間に合わなきゃ
それまでってだけだ
I'm not patient enough to wait until you're ready.
テメエの準備が整うまで
おとなしく待ってやるほど—
オレの気は長くねーぞ
They said they'd have faith in their ace and wait, but there's no such thing as a quick comeback in basketball.
（日向）いくら エースを
信じて待つって言っても—
バスケに 一発逆転はない
If the score versus the time remaining is out of hand by the time he perfects his copy, it's all over!
もしコピーができたところで
残り時間と点差が—
手遅れの状態だったら
全部 パアだぜ！？
I know!
（笠松）分かってら！
At this rate, a fifteen point difference...
このままだと 恐らく
15点差！ そこがデッドラインだ
That's our deadline!
He can't break through!
抜けない
They know what he's going to do!
完全に読まれてる
There's no way that'll go in! Rebound!
（今吉）
入るわけあらへん！ リバウンド
（笠松）これだったら
読みも クソも ねーだろ！
If I do this, your knowledge doesn't matter for shit.
Besides...
ついでに…
No one's better at getting offensive rebounds than Hayakawa!
オフェンス･リバウンドに
食らいつかせたら—
早川の右に出るヤツァ
いないんだよ！
クッソ このガキャー！
Damn it, this kid!
（ホイッスル）
（早川）よっしゃー！
Yeah!
He made the shot!
（観客１）決まった！
A twelve point difference!
（観客２）12点差だ
Sakurai?
（笠松）
桜井！？ しまった スリーポイント
Damn it, the three pointer...
If he makes it, we'll be down fifteen points!
決められたら 15点差
だああっ！
よし！
All right!
（小金井）おおお 止めたぁ！
He stopped him!
The point difference hasn't changed!
点差は そのままだ！
Senpai...
先輩…
Just focus on your own job.
いいから
オマエは 自分の仕事に集中しろよ
そのかわり 勝ったら—
In exchange, you can introduce me to girls if we win.
女の子 紹介 ヨロシク
合コンでも 可
I wouldn't mind a mixer.
なんスか！？ それ 森山さん！
What are you talking about, Moriyama?
（黄瀬）
黒子っちの言ってたこと—
I get the feeling I'm starting to understand what Kurokocchi said.
最近 ちょっと
分かったような気がするっス
黒子っちの言ってた“チーム”
そのために 何をすべきか
What Kurokocchi called a "team"...
What I need to do for them...
And what I need to do now.
そして オレが 今 何をすべきか
（青峰）
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
The only one who can beat me is me.
What if that "me" is who you're playing against?
じゃあ その“オレ”が相手なら
どうなるんスかね？
I'm sick of waiting.
（笠松）
待ちくたびれたぜ まったく…
Go crush them!
とっとと倒してこい！
Kise finally...
（日向）ついに 黄瀬が…
（伊月）エースの青峰を…
broke past...
（小金井）抜いたあ！
their ace, Aomine!
My bad feeling came true.
（今吉）悪い予感が当たりよった
I don't believe it.
信じられん 今の動きは文句なし
青峰の それや！
Those movements just now...
Those were Aomine's!
（海常部員たち）いけーっ！
調子に乗ってんじゃねぇぞ
黄瀬ぇ！
Don't get ahead of yourself, Kise!
No!
ダメーっ！
Defense, black No. 5!
ディフェンス 黒５番！
バスケットカウント！ ワンスロー
Basket counts, and one!
He made that shot?
（観客１）今の決まったのか？
When you're fouled and make your shot,
（観客２）ファウルされながら
シュートが入ったときは—
得点が認められて
フリースローが１本与えられるんだ
the basket counts, and you're awarded one free throw.
But more importantly...
それよりも—
青峰 ファウル ４つ目だ
that's Aomine's fourth foul!
（原澤）しまった…
Damn it...
He can't play so aggressively anymore!
もう 思いきったプレーは
できないぞ
They got us.
（今吉）やられた 布石は
もう１つ打たれとったんや
They had another trick up their sleeve.
なーにが 性格 悪いや
Who are you calling a bad guy?
You guys are way worse than me.
アンタらのほうが
よっぽど タチ悪いで ホンマ
Who said we weren't?
誰がいいなんて言ったよ
（今吉）ホンマ きっついで
This is really tough.
Not only has he perfected his copy,
つまりは
これで コピーされたあげくに—
ウチのエースは
まず 攻撃力 大幅ダウンや
but our ace's effectiveness has been significantly reduced.
Kaijo.....................................................................................Touou
He made the free throw!
ワンスローも決めた！
これで 差は １ケタだ！
It's only a single digit lead now!
（今吉）アカンわ
This isn't good.
まだ 第４クオーター
まるまる残して この状況
The entire fourth quarter's left, and we're in this situation.
We can't afford a nine point difference!
９点差なんて
あって ないようなもんや！
青峰！
Aomine!
（小金井）海常のカウンターだ！
Kaijo's countering!
Aomine fumbled?
（火神）青峰がファンブル！？
（桜井）絶対 止めなきゃ！
I have to stop him!
How is this possible?
なんで… 動きだけなら まだしも
速さまで 青峰さんと変わらない
Not only are his movements the same,
but he's just as fast as Aomine!
Slam it in, Kise!
ぶちこめ 黄瀬ー！
Those four fouls were my mistake.
（青峰）ったく ４ファウルは
オレのドジだった
けど これは
黄瀬の望んだ展開か？ 違うな
But is this what Kise was hoping for?
No... Even if he's accepted it as a winning strategy for his team,
チームが勝つための
戦略として受け入れてはいても—
本心じゃ
こうなってほしくなかったはずだ
this can't really be what he hoped for.
とはいえ
まさか あんなツラされるとはよ
But I never thought he'd make that face.
And what's Satsuki's problem?
しかも なんだ？ さつき
その心配そうなツラは
Why does she look so concerned?
Why do they look so panicked?
なんだ？ その あわてたツラは
Every last one of them...
どいつも こいつも
カン違いしてんじゃねーよ！
Don't get the wrong idea!
They've underestimated me if they think I'll back down just because I have four fouls.
（青峰）
４ファウルぐれえで—
腰が引けてると思われてたなんて
なめられたもんだぜ
けどなあ 特に
気に食わねえのが テメエだ 黄瀬
But you're the one who bothers me the most, Kise.
Don't show any concern for me.
いっちょ前に
気ぃ遣ってんじゃねーよ
そんなヒマあったら
死に物狂いで かかってきやがれ
If you can afford to do that,
you should be coming at me like your life depends on it!
いいっスね さすが
I knew you could do it.
あれで終わりじゃあ
拍子抜けも いいとこっス
If the game had ended like that, it would've been too easy.
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
（火神）再確認したぜ
これが“キセキの世代”
This reaffirms it...
This is the Generation of Miracles.
（黒子）全員 ぶっ倒して
日本一になります
We'll beat them all and become the best in Japan.
（火神）おう！ 燃えてきたぜ！
Yeah! I'm getting pumped!
Episode 25
My and Your Basketball